Looks like Open AI just made a major
move in the agentic no code space with
agent kit and it's basically their
answer to tools like nen vector shift as
well as langraph but native to open ai's
ecosystem and fully free to access right
now. Agent kit is a new endtoend
platform for building deploying and
optimizing AI agents with no coding
required. You have key components like
an agent builder which is a visual
canvas to design and test various sorts
of multi- aent workflows with a drag and
drop logic builtin guardrails and live
preview runs. You also have a connector
registry which is a central hub for
managing data sources APIs and tools
that connect across open AI products.
And lastly, you have a chat kit. This is
a customizable chat toolkit that lets
developers embed agentic UIs directly
into their products or websites. But
essentially with agent kit, OpenAI just
blurred the line between AI engineering
as well as no code automation which
gives anyone the power to create
productionready AI agents visually
similar to Nathan Zapier but with native
GPT integration and built-in Eva tools.
To get started, it's super simple. Just
head over to the open AI platform which
I'll leave a link to in the description
below. Head over to the agent builder
section and then over here you can open
up agent builder. This will take you to
create a new workflow from scratch. But
there's a couple of templates that you
can access readily like a document
comparison and internal knowledge
assistant data enrichment and so many
others. But we're going to go ahead and
create one from scratch. And this is
basically the new canvas of the agent
kit. Before we get started, I just want
to mention that you should definitely go
ahead and subscribe to the world of AI
newsletter. I'm constantly posting
different newsletters on a weekly basis.
So, this is where you can easily get
up-to-date knowledge about what is
happening in the AI space. So,
definitely go ahead and subscribe as
this is completely for free. But just
take a look at this example where
HubSpot integrated agent kit's custom
response vidget into their AI assistant.
And this is where it gives it the
capability to search the company's
knowledge base in real time. You can
retrieve the most relevant information
and help articles and deliver
personalized support responses directly
to users. This shows how Agent Kit isn't
just for devs. It's designed for real
businesses so that you can embed aic
logic into customer experiences without
building everything from scratch. And
obviously you can do the same thing with
Nathan, but this is something that's new
and that's why we're actually taking a
look at it so that we can compare and
see what sort of strengths there are for
agent kit. This is the canvas of the
agent builder. On the left hand side,
you have all the different nodes which
are basically action points. You have an
agent node which is where you can call
the model to perform any action with
instructions and tools. The end is where
you can basically finalize the workflow.
You have a start node and an end node.
Then you have other nodes like a
document node. You also have file
search, guard rails, MCPS. You also have
logics. So if and else logic, you can
also have it so that there's a loop for
different conditions, user approvals.
And then there's also data nodes where
you can reshape data as well as set
state where you can assign values to
workflow state variables. But this is
essentially where you can drag and drop
these different nodes to perform
different actions to automate different
things. But if you click on the agent
node, this is where you can give it a
name, give it an instruction as to what
you want it to perform like web
searching or you want to create an AI
agent that will help you process data.
You can then select the model of your
choice, a part of the open AI ecosystem,
which is definitely restrictive if
you're looking to use other models like
Gemini or Claude. But essentially once
you select that, you can uh toggle on or
off the reasoning effort. You can also
implement other tools you can use like a
client tool, MCPS, file search and etc.
You have all the different tools that
open a provides. And if you click more,
there's other options that you can
tweak, which I wouldn't recommend you do
right away if you do not know what
you're doing. But just take a look at
this demo workflow, which is a simple
workflow to research a set of companies
using web search and provide a summary
analysis. This is where you first start
off with the user inquiry, which sends
it over to the web research agent. This
web research agent has been configured
and it also has been given a name and a
couple of instructions where it's stated
that you are a helpful assistant. Use
web search capabilities to find
information about the following company
that could be used in marketing assets
based on the underlying logic. From
there it works on the next step and that
is to summarize and display. This is the
next agent that has been configured with
another model like the GPT5 and it also
has been uh requested to include chat
history and instruction to put the
research together in a nice display
using the output format that was
described and alternatively you can
convert the results into different
structures. But now what we can do is we
can actually take a preview look of
this. So if you click on preview, you
can test this out and we can say
something like analyze Nvidia the stock
and then we can send in this request and
you can see that now it is working on
using the web research agent where it's
looking through different sources like
Nvidia's website or description and it's
now working on a summary and displaying
that content. And you can see right here
that it has done that by providing me
the company name, the industry which is
on semiconductors and technology
headquarters in Santa Clair, company
size, website, bonding year, as well as
a description of what the company does.
And this was a super simple AI agent
that anyone can create with most AI
agent builders. And you can see how easy
it was to actually configure with the
agent kit. And after you have configured
your agent, you can click on evaluation.
This is where you can get a good
understanding of the log as well as how
the agent is performing and you can
evaluate different traces with different
tests. Now you can also duplicate this.
You can access the code code for the
chatkit as well as the agent SDK and
then you can also add a domain to this.
And once you have finished configuring
it, you can then publish your AI agent
so that anyone can access it or you can
basically access it in a production
environment. Here is another demo
example of an AI agent that can perform
different sorts of actions by invoking
the database. So you can get analysis on
different files a part of your database
with different guard rules that are set
so that it accesses it only if user
input doesn't violate the moderation.
It'll then identify each category and
then it will provide you a summary of
it. And you can actually take a preview
of this by sending in a prompt like how
many orders did you sell in 2015 and you
can send in this prompt and if it passes
the guardrail it will then execute it
using the select agent and it will
select the current the correct condition
and then provide you the correct answer
afterwards. So you can see that it was
able to invoke our database. And the
total orders is 82k approximately based
off of the dummy data that was set. And
this is something that can also process
large amounts of documents which is
great. Now here comes the real question.
Is it better than nan? Well the simple
answer is Asian kit is definitely not
superior than n just yet. This is
because agent kit is definitely fairly
new. There's a lot of factors that are
still being implemented, but most of the
reasons why I prefer nan right away is
because it's a little easier to work
with, which also offers a lot of
customizable and versatility. You have
the ability to use a lot of different
nodes in comparison to agent kit, which
is just restricted to the base amount
which we saw over there. There's more
agents. There's more flexibility with
models you can use. And it's easier to
prototype to production with the
pipelines in Nathan. Now, this doesn't
mean that agent kit is bad. It's
definitely a great alternative that you
can access directly on the web for free,
and it's powered by a state-of-the-art
models, so you can't really complain
much when you're getting offered free
access to it. It's something that will
be worked upon more, and it will be able
to maybe even be on par with Nan in the
future. So in my opinion right now, NE
is better for multi-providers as well as
higher customizable workflows and agent
kit is something that you can get
started with completely for free today
and get started on the cloud to build
basic automations. If you like this
video and would love to support the
channel, you can consider donating to my
channel through the super thanks option
below. Or you can consider joining our
private Discord where you can access
multiple subscriptions to different AI
tools for free on a monthly basis, plus
daily AI news and exclusive content,
plus a lot more. But that's basically
it, guys, for today's video on agent
kit. This is something that I'll leave a
link to in the description below so that
you can easily get started. But with
that thought, guys, thank you guys so
much for watching. Make sure you go
ahead and subscribe to the second
channel. This where I'm also posting
consistently with my partners. Make sure
you go ahead and join the newsletter,
join our private Discord, follow me on
Twitter, and lastly, make sure you guys
subscribe, turn on notification bell,
like this video, and please take a look
at our previous videos cuz there's a lot
of content that you will truly benefit
from. But with that thought, guys, have
an amazing day, spread positivity, and
I'll see you guys fairly shortly. He
saw.